Finding Aid for Erie and Kalamazoo Railroad records, 1834-1968
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Erie and Kalamazoo Railroad records 1834-1968
Erie and Kalamazoo Railroad.
12 linear feet and 2 oversize volumes
851226 Bb 2
The first railroad west of the Appalachians. Correspondence, legal papers, receipts, account books, bank statements, and stock certificate books; also reports to the Interstate Commerce Commission and Michigan and Ohio regulatory agencies. and minutes, 1834-1919, of the Board of Directors.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were donated by the company (donor no. 3047 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Erie and Kalamazoo Railroad was chartered on April 22, 1833, to connect Port Lawrence (later named Toledo) with western Michigan. Later, as a part of the Lake Shore and Michigan Southern, the New York Central, the Penn Central and the Conrail systems, the railroad carried passengers until November 1956.
The Erie and Kalamazoo Railroad record group consists of minutes, correspondence, annual reports to regulatory agencies, and various business and legal documents, including payrolls, stock transfers, dividends paid, and check registers.
Subjects:
Erie and Kalamazoo Railroad.; Railroads--Michigan.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Erie and Kalamazoo Railroad.; Railroads--Michigan.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Prints.
- Organizational records
  - Minute book, 1834-1919 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1840-1952 (Box 1)
    - 1840-1914, 29 folders
    - 1915-1939, 32 folders (Box 2)
    - 1939-1952 and undated, 25 folders (Box 3)
  - Business papers, 1834-1918, 47 folders (Box 4)
    (include payrolls, stock transfers, wills, and other legal documents)
  - Business papers, 1919-1952, 33 folders (Box 5)
    (missing 1951)
  - Annual Reports to Interstate Commerce Commission (Box 6)
  - Annual Reports to the Public Utilities Commission of Ohio (Box 6)
  - Annual Reports to the Railroad Commission of the State of Michigan, 1915-1918 and 1935-1938 (Box 7)
  - Minutes of meetings of company stockholders, 1921-1959 (Box 7)
  - Ledger, 1848-1849 (Box 7)
  - Journal, 1848-1849 (Box 7)
  - Publications
    - Leases and contracts (Box 7)
    - Mortgages (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous: notes and research material, etc. (Box 7)
  - Michigan Historical Collections file (re transfer of records to the library) (Box 7)
  - Postcards containing print image of the railroad (Box 7)
  - Letterpress books, 1902-1913, 2 volumes (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous business papers (Box 8)
  - Check registers (Box 9)
  - Check registers (Box 10)
  - Stock certificate books (Box 10)
  - Check registers (Box 11)
  - Correspondence and unprocessed miscellanea, ca. 1943-1968 (Box 12)
  - Dividend books
    - 1885-1922 (Volume 1)
    - 1939-1946 (Volume 2)
    - 1946-1948 (Box 12)
      (unbound)